# **Damilare** Odunayo Samuel

sdamilare420@gmail.com 🔀

08163502922

07080491060 1, John Adebiyi Street, Off Igando Road, Ikotun, Lagos

https://www.linkedin.com/in/damilaresamuel26 in

## CAREER OBJECTIVE

A freelance software developer who seeks to become a successful expert in the field of Information Technology by channeling technical knowledge and skills to ensure professional and personal growth. A dedicated and enthusiastic individual who seeks to work for an organization which provides the opportunity to improve skills and knowledge to growth along with the organization.

#### **EDUCATION**

**MSc in Computer Science** 

University of Lagos 2019 (In view)

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science Lagos State University 2011- 2015

**SSCE** 

Golden Touch College 2004 - 2010

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Web design Frontend Trainer (Contract)

Ekobits ICT Academy (17th Aug 2020 - 11 Sept 2020)

- Introduced concept of web design and development to students.
- Taught fundamentals of web in html and css to the students.
- Explained concepts such as image tag, forms, links, flex, external styling etc.
- Formulated manuals for them while giving helpful links to them.
- Introduced GitHub for the storage of their projects.
- Guided the participants in developing and hosting their websites on github.

#### **Python Backend Trainer (Contract)**

#### Ekobits ICT Academy (June 2020 - July 2020)

- Taught basic python to the trainees and gave tasks to test their knowledge.
- Explained backend stacks such as flask and django to the trainees using a project based approach.
- Developed a todo-app model in flask and django and then created rest APIs for the models so as to be consumed by front end stacks in react js and vue js.
- Monitored student's performance to see student's progress.
- Guided the students all through to their project defense.

#### Python/Data Science Trainee

#### Bincom ICT Solutions (Mar 2019 - Apr 2019)

- Received training on basics of Python and some fundamentals in data analysis. such as the use of libraries including NumPy and Pandas.
- Learnt how to create a simple hello world website using Django.
- Collaborated with team members to debug basic python issues.

#### **Software Developer Trainee**

#### Moat Academy for Developers (Jan 2019 - Mar 2019)

- Learned and designed front end graphics for websites.
- Developed team communication skills for weekly projects.
- Learned and performed software testing to uncover bugs and troubleshoot
- Learned and developed ER diagrams for databases using MySQL Workbench tool.
- Learned about the Flask framework.
- · Developed a web application project that help the masses especially university students within Lagos find hostels and houses using Flask and MySQL database.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Blog Application**

#### **Side Project**

- Designed a blog application that performs CRUD operations using the Django Framework.
- Technologies used include: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, SQLite and Django.

#### To-Do App Side project

- Designed a todo-application that allows the users to keep a list of their daily tasks and plans.
- Technologies used include: React and Django REST.

#### **Website Developer**

- Designed a school website which allows the school to connect to the public and pass across information which before wasn't readily accessible.
- Technologies used include: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, Django and Postgres DB.
- Link: https://newworldischolar.com

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming Language: Python
- Frameworks and Web: Django, Django REST, Flask, Bootstrap4, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Version Control: Git
- Databases: MySQL, Postgres DB and SQLite
- Cloud Services: Digital Ocean, Heroku and Google Cloud.

### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- Quick learner with good grasping ability
- Great team player
- Apt listener
- Practical-oriented and result focused
- •Good time management skill

## **REFERENCE**

Available on request

S